<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Caoraa</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-caoraa.xml" url="https://github.com/TavorCohen/Heloderma/blob/elements/race-caoraa.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Caoraa" type="Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HMBRW_RACE_CAORAA">
		<description>
			<p>The caoraa are humanoid sheep, standing on a pair of hoofed feet and sheep-like hind legs. They have 4 groups of people in their species, the first called sheepkin have heads like human females except with slightly animalistic facial features and sheep-like ears. They are smaller then their male counterparts, they have very fluffy puffy hair on their heads like sheep wool, that tends to get matted if not brushed often. Their lower and upper bodies resemble that of human females, although with most of their body covered in wool-like curly and puffy hair. Except for their upper arms, a bit of their stomach, their inner thighs having no hair, they also have a pair of small horns and a tail.</p>
			<p class="indent">The second are called ramkin, they are generally the largest of the caoraa and their facial features are more animalistic than that of sheepkin. Though their looks are the same, except for their heads, lower and upper bodies resembling that of human males and their body hair is shorter as well as thinner than sheepkin. The third being goatkin who consist of both males and females. They look generally the same as the sheepkin or ramkin, but have features like goats and with smaller more lighter builds. The final one being dearkin who also consist of both males and females. The deerkin have features that resemble that of deer, elk or moose. They look generally the same as the sheepkin, ramkin, or goatkin but taller then ramkin and don't have as big of builds as the ramkin do.</p>
			<h4>HISTORY</h4>
			<p>The caoraa were made after the elves, by the goddesses of the highland plains, woodlands and mountains, the goddess Fillydia and her two sisters Sidhae and Bhéara. Fillydia is seen as a woman in a green dress with gilded antlers, who can shapeshift into the form of a red deer. Sidhae who appears in the form of a golden-haired woman in a black dress, holding a harp and can take the form of a golden-haired goat. Bhéara who appears in the form of either a beautiful girl with white hair or a pure white sheep. The caoraa are split between three different groups, the first group is comprised of mostly deerkin. They are nomads who travel all across the land and make temporary livings in woodlands, or forests. They have been a very neutral party among the 3 groups and have had very little if not no wars or infighting throughout the years. The second group which make their homes and villages on the sides of mountains are the goatkin. They live a solitary life in the mountains where they live, being miners and farmers they produce a lot of the crafts and more valuable materials for the caoraa kingdom. While the third and last of the three groups consists mostly of ramkin and sheepkin it is also the main hub for their race's entire kingdom. Housing the monarch of their people, most of their schools, and as well as their more important facilities. The whole and very large city act as a hub as stated earlier, housing most of the more wealthier folk and other buildings. While surrounding the outside of the city, are many houses as well as farmland plots for most of the caoraa people to live in. Most of the caoraa kingdom as a whole is littered with many small villages and towns. This is due to their land consisting of many vast open plains, and littered with forests as well as mountains. This makes it somewhat difficult to traverse for normal people, causing most foreign travelers trouble when traveling around. The caoraa have had a few scuffles with dragonborn, and a few with orcs or half-orcs through the years, but for the most part they generally ignore most if not all races. While having most outside dramas ignored, the caoraa themselves have had many cases of infighting and civil wars. The caoraa have gone through many different monarchs throughout their peoples history and have had many revolutions with so many different winners as well as losers. Their own capital's construction wasn't free from such infighting and problems. The main capital of the caoraa people is a large city, that was built by the third monarch of the caoraa people. The project took many years to build, lots of hard labor, as well as a lot of wealth, being put towards its construction. This ended up with the monarchy's coffers becoming sparse, and then they themselves being overtaken by another party in the process. The current ruling party has been in power for about 35 years, which is the third longest time a monarch of the caoraa people has ever ruled.</p>
			<h4>SOCIETY</h4>
			<p>The main bulk of the caoraa are very lively free people, farming and living out their lives to the fullest for them is very important. Most caoraa like to stick with down to earth-like mentalities, meaning stay with the earth, be with the earth and beliefs like that. Though they don't have many religions or even taboos the caoraa believe in two things wholly above all others. The first is, that one should not fight another for no absolute reason, and that to do so is looked down upon. The second is, that no matter what all caoraa were made by the goddesses of the highland plains, and that to say otherwise is grounds for severe punishment. The caoraa are known as very stubborn people, in most cases when caoraa are at odds with another, they butt heads. This is both figuratively, as well as literally and they are quite hard to reason with when they get angry or frustrated enough. Now this is more commonly found among ramkin and goatkin, but other caoraa aren't immune to this personality trait as well and can lead to trouble when a problem needs solving. When it comes to sheepkin, or deerkin however they mostly are quite calm and reasonable. This usually means that they are the ones who end up having to fix the problems the other caoraa cause. Now it is a fact that caoraa are omnivores, quite odd given their more herbivore appearance and features. But while this is true, most caoraa diets consist of breads, grains, and vegetables. The caoraa are also quite fond of milk as well as cheeses, which to some may seem against their supposed abstain of carnivorous dietary items, but it doesn't seem like that is the case. Caoraa though are known around the world that they live in, to be not only the best brewers of bear, but also the best drinkers of it. To the caoraa brewing is an art form, and many of their most common fights or arguments with one another are over which brew is the best. This usually ends up into a drunken bar brawl, which is only ended until they either pass out from fighting, or the booze finally puts them out. This is the reason why most caoraa have a bad reputation among other races, as being absolute drunkards and roughhousing thick skull idiots.</p>
			<h4>CAORAA TRAITS</h4>
			<p>As a caoraa, you have the following racial traits. </p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creature Type.</em></strong> You are a Humanoid.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> You are Medium or Small. You choose the size when you select this race.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sure-Footed.</em></strong> You have advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Gore.</em></strong> Your horns are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Herd Mentality.</em></strong> As long as you can see an ally within 15 feet of you, you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> Caoraa are partitioned in the deerkin, goatkin, ramkin and sheepkin subraces. Pick one.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Craftiness.</strong> You have proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, Investigation, Medicine, Sleight of Hand, or Survival.</li>
				<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Defiance.</strong> You have advantage on saving throws to avoid or end the frightened condition on yourself.</li>
				<li style="margin-left:1em;text-indent:-1em;"><strong>Draconic Sorcery.</strong> You know one cantrip of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma is your spellcasting ability for that cantrip (choose when you select this race).</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Option (Caoraa)" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size (Caoraa)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_SMALL|ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_MEDIUM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (CAORAA)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SURE_FOOTED" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_GORE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HERD_MENTALITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CAORAA_SUBRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Sure-Footed" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SURE_FOOTED">
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Gore" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_GOR">
		<description>
			<p>Your horns are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your horns are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal 1d6 + {{strength:modifier}} piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Herd Mentality" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HERD_MENTALITY">
		<description>
			<p>As long as you can see an ally within 15 feet of you, you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As long as you can see an ally within 15 feet of you, you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Caoraa Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CAORAA_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>Caoraa are partitioned in the deerkin, goatkin, ramkin and sheepkin subraces.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Caoraa Subrace" supports="Caoraa" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Deerkin Caoraa" type="Sub Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_SUB_RACE_DEERKIN_CAORAA">
		<supports>Elf</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Graceful Deer.</em></strong> Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mask of the Wild.</em></strong> You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Deerkin Caoraa)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />

			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_GRACEFUL_DEER" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MASK_OF_THE_WILD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fleet of Foot" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_GRACEFUL_DEER">
		<description>
			<p>Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your speed increases to 35 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="35" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mask of the Wild" type="Racial Trait" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MASK_OF_THE_WILD">
		<description>
			<p>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
